Not everyone who runs a city is elected.
King of New York is a thriller, crime film directed by Abel Ferrara.
A former drug lord returns from prison determined to wipe out all his competition and distribute the profits of his
operations to New York's poor and lower classes in this stylish and ultra violent modern twist on Robin Hood.
Frank White, played by Christopher Walken.
Dennis Gilley, played by David Caruso.
Jimmy Jump, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Roy Bishop, played by Victor Argo.
Thomas Flanigan, played by Wesley Snipes.
Jennifer, played by Janet Julian.
King of New York is a 1990 neo-noir crime drama film directed
by Abel Ferrara and written by Nicholas St.
It stars Christopher Walken, Laurence Fishburne, David Caruso, Victor Argo and Wesley Snipes, with supporting
roles played by Giancarlo Esposito, Steve Buscemi, Paul Calderón, Janet Julian and Theresa Randle.
Walken portrays Frank White, a New York City drug kingpin rebuilding his criminal empire
after his release from prison, while also attempting to go legitimate.
The film was released by Carolco Pictures (through New
Line Cinema) on September 28, 1990.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with several
criticizing the film's violence and dark tone.
Retrospective reviews have been much more positive, and the
film has been described as one of Ferrara's best.
The film explores themes of new york city, gangster,
release from prison, hope, cocaine.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.